http://www.wdt.edu/about/student-consumer-information/data-privacy

Skip to Main Content
Skip to Primary Navigation
Business And ComputersAccountingBookkeepingBusiness & TechnologyBusiness - EntrepreneurshipBusiness - HospitalityBusiness Office ProfessionalBusiness - Social Media MarketingComputer ScienceFarm & Ranch ManagementLibrary TechnicianConstruction And ManufacturingComputer-Aided DesignConstruction TechnologyDrafting and Machining TechnologyElectrical TradesHVAC & Refrigeration TechnologyPlumbing TechnologyPrecision Machining TechnologyWelding and FabricationEnergy And Environmental TechnologiesEnvironmental Engineering Technician – Controlled Environment AgricultureElectrical TradesEnvironmental Engineering TechFarm & Ranch ManagementElectrical Trades – MechnicianHealth SciencesAllied HealthDental AssistingHealth Information ManagementMedical AssistingMedical Laboratory TechnicianParamedicPharmacy TechnicianPhlebotomy/Laboratory AssistantPractical NursingRegistered NursingSurgical TechnologyLegal And Public ServicesCriminal JusticeEmergency Medical Technician (EMT)Criminal Justice - Law Enforcement EmphasisParamedicTransportation TechnologiesAutomotive TechnologyDiesel TechnologyDiesel Technology – Industrial MaintenanceSee All Degree ProgramsHigh School Students Earn college credits NOW with Dual Enrollment Classes!Learn About Dual EnrollmentLoginsMyWDTStudent EmailFaculty and Staff Email CancelSite SearchGO CancelDegree ProgramsCurrent StudentsFuture StudentsParentsLoginsAbout
Corporate Education Center
Employment Opportunities
Directory
Human Resources
Foundation & Alumni
Library
Medical Simulation Center
News & Events
Paying for School
Student Life and Success
Student Success Center
Western Dakota Tech Learn. Do. Now.
Visit Us
Request Info
Chat Online
Data Privacy
Western Dakota Tech respects the privacy of website visitors. This page is intended to inform you of what information is collected by this site and how the information is used. Your use of websites is subject to the privacy statement of the providers of those sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave this site and to read the privacy statement on each site you visit. Often, you can tell you are leaving the Western Dakota Tech website by looking at the URL of the destination site.
Information Practices
Western Dakota Tech understands that security and privacy are important issues for visitors to their website (the “site”) and recognizes their obligations to keep your information secure and confidential. That is why the WDT maintains the following standards to help protect information that personally identifies you.
Collection of Information
Western Dakota Tech does not collect personal information about you when you visit our site unless you choose to make such information available to us. You may be asked to voluntarily provide your name, address, phone number, email address or other personally identifiable information (“personal information”) to have access to some features of the Site. You may always refuse to provide your personal information, and this may lead to our inability to provide you with certain offerings, services or products. We or our business partners may also collect information that is anonymous, such as your IP address (a number used to identify your computer on the Internet) or the type of browser you are using (“anonymous information”), through the use of cookies or by other means. We hope that, by using Anonymous Information, we can update the site to make it more useful to you and other users. We reserve the right to maintain, update, disclose or otherwise use anonymous information, without limitation.
Use of Information
WDT uses your personal information for the following purposes: to process your requests; to administer and improve the site and related services; to notify you of our offerings, services and products that may be of interest to you; to provide Internet security; and to meet legal requirements. WDT may work with associated businesses which may perform certain functions on our behalf, such as sending email messages, managing data, processing credit card payments or providing services to users. These businesses have access to your personal information only to the extent necessary to perform these specific functions and may not use it for any other purpose. We may use third-party advertising companies to place ads on the Site and to place our ads on other websites. If WDT is involved in the sale of a substantial portion of its business assets, anonymous or personal information may be among the transferred assets.
Privacy of Children
WDT encourages parents and guardians to be aware of and participate in their children’s online activities. We strictly adhere to the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act and will not knowingly collect, use or disclose personal information from any child under the age of 13 in any manner that violates this law.
Your Opportunity to Opt-out of Email Advertising, Promotional Information
Email - In the event you do not wish to receive promotional email from Western Dakota Tech, follow the opt-out instructions contained within the body of any email message you receive.Mail, Text Messages, Telephone Calls, Email directly from Admissions - To opt out of receiving these types of promotional information, call Admissions at 605-718-2565 or email Admissions@wdt.edu and ask to be removed from any mailing or contact list.
Cookies
When you visit the site, WDT or a third party may store or recognize some information on your computer in the form of a “cookie” or similar file that can help us in many ways. For example, cookies allow us to tailor the site to better match your interests and preferences. With most Internet browsers or other software, you can erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please refer to your browser instructions to learn more about these functions. If you reject cookies, functionality of the site may be limited, and you may not be able to take advantage of some of the site’s features.
Links
The site may contain links to other sites on the Internet that are owned and operated by third parties. If you access those links, you will leave the WDT website. WDT does not control those third-party sites or their privacy practices, which may differ from WDT’s privacy practices. WDT does not endorse or make any representations about third-party websites. The personal data you choose to provide to or that is collected by those third parties is not covered by the WDT Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any website before submitting your personal information.
WDT may also provide social media features on the site that enable you to share information with your social networks and to interact with us on various social media sites. Your use of these features may result in the collection or sharing of information about you, depending on the feature. We encourage you to review the privacy policies and settings on the social media sites with which you interact to make sure you understand the information that could be shared by those sites.
Security
We have policies and procedures in place to protect the privacy and confidentiality of your personal information that we collect and maintain. All personal information is stored on our secured servers, behind a firewall at a data center with access to data strictly controlled. Any unauthorized use of the site may result in criminal and/or civil prosecution.
Phishing Scams
It is a policy of WDT to not send unsolicited emails seeking certain highly sensitive personal information, such as social security number, date of birth or credit card number. In the event you receive such an email, and you have not previously been in direct contact with its sender, please do not respond and do not open any attachments as they may contain malicious code that will infect your computer.
Changes to Data Privacy
We may modify data privacy practices at any time by posting revised information here, with an updated effective date. Accordingly, we urge you to frequently review this information. By using the site and providing us with your personally identifiable information, you consent to our use of such information as described on this page.
Contacting WDT or Modifying Your Personal Information
If you have any questions or comments about WDT's data privacy practices contact Pam Stillman-Rokusek, Director of Strategic Communications and Marketing, at Pam.Stillman-Rokusek@wdt.edu. To update your personal information provided to Western Dakota Tech, contact Debbie Toms, Student Success Director and Registrar, at Deborah.Toms@wdt.edu.  Please provide a concise communication with complete information, including your contact information.
Student Consumer Information
Federal Reporting
Program Disclosures
Data Privacy
Student Diversity
Student Right to Know
WESTERN DAKOTA TECH MISSIONWestern Dakota Technical College prepares students to be highly-skilled professionals through accessible, career-focused programs to improve their lives, while adapting to community workforce needs and positively impacting our economy.
Join the Conversation
Connect with Western Dakota Tech
Like Us On Facebook
Follow Us On Twitter
Watch Us On YouTube
Website Powered By PageFramer, Development By Robert Sharp & Associates
